（上条(かみじょう)）
波乱の夏休みが
終わりを告げた９月１日
September 1st, the day that marks the end of one storm of a summer vacation.
The transfer student that showed up was... Index...
現れた転入生は インデックス
No, I mean, Himegami.
…ではなくて 姫神(ひめがみ)だった
インデックスといた
風斬氷華(かざきり ひょうか)っていう女の子と一緒に
With Kazakiri Hyouka, the girl that appeared with Index,
俺たちは 地下街に遊びに出かけた
we went to hang out in the underground mall.
Of course, we didn't have a clue something like this would happen then.
もちろん こんなことが
起きていようとは 知る由もなく
～♪
#22 Golem
（店員）
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much.
That was delicious!
（インデックス）
ああ おいしかった
おなか
ポンポンポンのポーン
My tummy is all bomb, bomb, bomb, and bomb.
What's this? What's this?
There's so many TVs set up here.
なんか
テレビが いっぱい置いてある
あっ！　わあ…
こんなテレビ見たの初めて！
This is the first time I've seen a TV like this!
Umm, that's not a TV but a-
（風斬）
あの… それはテレビじゃなくて…
うん？　電話？
A phone call?
Go on in.
（上条）中に入っててくれ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん
Okay!
Let's go, let's go, Hyouka.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
行こう 行こう 氷華
Hello?
はい
（ノイズ）
Th... is... Hi...e....ami...
（女性）…だけど
（上条）うん？
...Hur...y...R...n...
（女性）…けて
まあ 地下街だしな
Well, we are underground...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
これ かわいい
These are so cute...
Cute, cute, cute!!
かわいい かわいい かわいい
ねえねえ かわいいよ 氷華
This is so cute, Hyouka!
Y-Yeah...
うん？　あっ！　なに あれ
What's that?!
This type is pretty good, don't ya think?
（女性）
服の種類 多いから
すっごい いいよね
（女性）
うん
あのメイドのも かわいかった
That maid one is cute, too.
（風斬）あっ… ほら あっち
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん？
See, over there?
（風斬）
写真シールの撮影用に―
I think they're renting clothing...
...for photo printing here.
服の貸し出しサービスを
やってるんだと思う
うわぁ！　面白そう！
That's so fun!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ねえ やろう やろう
（風斬）私は… アッ…
Let's try it, let's try it!
But I-
Index!
インデックス どこだ？
Where are you?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
うわぁ すご～い！
Wow!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
「超機動少女(マジカルパワード)カナミン」の―
There's Magical Powered Kanamin's dress here, too!
ドレススーツがある
（風斬）あの… それ 着るの？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）着る着る！
Umm, are we wearing these?
Yes, yes!!!
ここか
They're in this one?
おい インデックス
Hey, Index.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
あっ ととと… 当麻
T-T-T-Touma!
Umm, we'd be very troubled if you came in now.
（風斬）
あの… 今 開けてもらうと困ります
フン… 上条さんは
保健室の轍(てつ)は踏みませんのことよ
This Kamijyo Touma won't repeat the same mistake he made back in the nurse's room.
Huh, wait, don't push.
（風斬）
うわ！　ちょっと 押さないで…
ウワッ！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）はい 氷華　半分こ
（風斬）うん
Here, Hyouka.
Half and half.
Okay.
これが学校生活か　いいな いいな
So this is "school" life.
It's so fun!
現実には 退屈な授業とか
地獄みてえなテストとかあってだな
The reality is there are boring classes and hellish exams, you know?
（風斬）あれ？
（上条）うん？
（風斬）聞こえた？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん
Did you hear that?
Yeah.
What's wrong, you two?
どうしたんだ？　２人とも
I think I heard a voice from somewhere.
（風斬）今 どこからか声が…
（上条）声？
Voice?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
なんか 頭の中から
直接 声が聞こえたような
It's like a voice is directly speaking to our brains.
Brains?
（上条）
頭の中って そりゃ…
Are you-
（風紀委員(ジャッジメント)）そこのあなた
（上条たち）あっ…
You over there!
（風紀委員）
人が こんだけ注意しているのに
なに のんびりしてんのよ？
I've been calling for your attention all this time.
How dare you act so indifferently!
風紀委員(ジャッジメント)？ …で 何か？
A Judgment person...
And... what do you want?
ハァ… あのね
Excuse me~
Telepathy, telepathy!
だから テレパシーよ テレパシー
聞こえてるんでしょう？　ほら
You heard my voice, didn't you?
See?
Do you understand the situation now?
これで状況は分かってもらえた？
No, not at all.
（上条）いや 全然
（風紀委員）ハァ…
おかしいわね　どうして
あなたには届かないのかしら
That's weird...
How come it's not reaching you?
I'll explain it by mouth then.
口頭で説明するわ
A terrorist has come down into this underground mall.
現在 この地下街に
テロリストが紛れ込んでいるの
Terrorist?
テロリスト？
うん　まもなく 隔壁を下ろして
地下街を閉鎖します
We will be lowering the walls and closing off the underground mall.
速やかに退避してください
いいですね？
Please evacuate immediately.
Okay?
This doesn't look good.
なんかマズそうだな
とにかく ここを出るか
Let's get out of here then.
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
見～つけた　フフフフッ…
Found you~
（上条）何なんだ？　これは
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん？
What the hell is this?!
土より出(い)でる人の虚像
The artificial giant born from primal clay.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
神殿の守護たるゴーレムを―
Someone's forcefully made the guardian of the temple,
Golem, into an English guardian angel.
無理やりに
英国の守護天使に置き換えてる
…てことは
テロリストって魔術師なのか？
That means... the terrorist is a magician?!
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
さあ パーティーを始めましょう
Now, let the party begin.
Scream as much as you can
in this mud-stinking tomb covered in clay!
土のかぶった泥くせえ墓穴の中で
存分に鳴きやがれ
（上条たち）
ウワッ！
（地響き）
（上条たち）ウワッ！
（明かりの消える音）
何だ？
What the?
Hey, let us out!
（男性）
おい 出してくれ！
（女性）ちょっと なに？
（男性）開けろ！
What's going on?!
Open up!
Index, go with Kazakiri and hide somewhere!
インデックス
風斬と どこかに隠れてろ
No, you go hide with Hyouka, Touma!
当麻こそ 氷華と隠れてて
敵が魔術師なら
これは私の仕事なんだよ
If the enemy is a magician, then this is my duty!
How are you able to fight with those thin arms of yours?
お前の細腕で
ケンカなんかできるかよ？
ンッ… 当麻 今までのラッキーが
自分の実力だと思ってない？
Touma, are you starting to think your lucky wins are actually because of skill?
所詮 当麻は魔術の素人なんだから
You're just an amateur of magic, Touma.
ハッ！　何をおっしゃいますやら
Hah. I thought you could come up with something better.
この不幸の塊である上条さんに
ラッキーなんかあるはずねえだろう
This Kamijyo-san, the manifestation of misfortune, cannot possibly have any luck.
自分で言ってて イヤになる
...I hate myself for saying that...
U-Umm...
あ… あの…
なんだか よく分かんないですけど
I'm not too sure what's going on,
but is there anything I can help-
（風斬）私が何か手伝えること…
（上条･ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ない！
No!
Hide Index!
Run, you two!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻 逃げて
（上条）隠れろ インデックス
（２人）
ウワッ！
Did you hear the meowing of a cat?
（黒子(くろこ)）
あら？　猫の鳴き声が
聞こえませんでしたか？
Yeah...
（上条）
いてて…
Oww...
Hey.
（美琴）ねえ
（上条）うん？
What the hell are you doing in a place like this?
こんなとこで何やってるわけ？
My, my.
あらあら
こんな時間から大胆ですこと
Getting so steamy so quickly?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
ンンッ… なに 当麻？
What, Touma?
この品のない女たちは一体 誰？
知り合い？
Who are these classless women?
Your acquaintances?!
Hey you.
あんたね 初対面の相手に―
Calling someone you meet for the first time "classless"...
いきなり “品がない”って
どういうこと？
What is your problem?
You are Touma's acquaintance?!
あなた
やっぱり 当麻の知り合いなの？
What's your relationship with Touma?
当麻とは一体 どんな関係？
R-Relationship?
か… 関係って…
ンンッ…
あんたこそ こいつの何なのよ？
And... And what are you to him anyway?
えっ？　えっと…
命の恩人だったりする
Umm... he kind of saved my life?
はぁ？　あんたも 頼んでないのに
駆けつけてくれたクチ？
Huh?
You're another "I didn't ask for help but he came to help anyway"?
Touma!
You!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻！
（美琴）あんた！
Y-Yes!
はい！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ･美琴）
どういうことか説明してもらうわよ
I think I'd like to hear your explanation here.
Mind giving a little explanation?
えっ… えっと…
U-Umm...
I see.
なるほど　大体 怪しいと
思っていたのですけど
I thought it was fishy,
but Oneesama has already opened her heart and body to Kamijyo Touma, eh?
お姉様は 私を差し置いて―
上条さんに身も心も全てを
さらけ出したというわけですわね
さらけ出してなんかないわよ！
I have not!!!
And?
…で？　あんた
今度は どんなトラブルに―
What kind of trouble did you get yourself in this time?
巻き込まれてるわけ？
知るかよ
Beats me.
Shirai, what exactly is the situation?
白井(しらい)　一体 どういう状況なんだ？
There is a terrorist active in this underground mall.
この地下街で
テロリストが活動中のようです
大規模な戦闘が
起きる可能性がありますので
There is a possibility that a large-scale battle will happen,
so I need to evacuate the civilians that are still trapped.
私は 閉じ込められた方たちの
避難を済ませませんと
My skill is teleport, after all.
これでもテレポートの使い手ですし
お前は
こいつらを外に出してやってくれ
You take these girls out then.
I will buy you some time-
その間 俺が時間を稼ぐ…
You're the one that should be running away first.
（２人）
あんたが先に逃げるの！
つってもな…
But...
俺の右手は
あらゆる能力を無効化させちまう
My right hand can neutralize any kind of power.
That's why I need to stay here.
だから ここに残るしかねえんだよ
There is a limit to my power, as well.
（黒子）
私の力にも 限りがあります
I can only teleport two people at a time.
一度に運べるのは
２人が限度でしょう
Then, get Index and Kazakiri out first.
（上条）
そんじゃ
まずは インデックスと風斬を頼む
Touma, that means you want to stay here with this short-hair, huh?
当麻　それは つまり
この短髪と残ると言いたいんだね？
Then, get Misaka and Kazakiri out.
（上条）
じゃ 御坂(みさか)と風斬でいいや
Oh, you want to stay here with this midget, I see...
ほう… あんたは
この ちっこいのと残りたいと
Such misfortune...
（上条）
不幸だ
では お２人とも
Then, you two.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）えっ？
（美琴）ちょっと！
Wait!
悪いな お前を残しちまって
Sorry.
You ended up having to stay here.
ううん　私は別に
それより あなたのほうこそ…
No, I'm fine.
Besides, you-
（地響き）
（上条）ウワッ！
It started?
始まったか
Sorry, Kazakiri.
悪い 風斬　お前は ここで
白井が来るのを待っててくれ
Wait here until Shirai comes back.
えっ… えっ あなたは？
W-What about you?
魔術師を止めてくる
I'm going to go stop the magician.
It doesn't work at all!
（黄泉川(よみかわ)）
全然 効かないじゃん
The evacuation of the students isn't complete yet!
（警備員(アンチスキル)Ａ）
まだ学生たちの避難は
終わっていません
Your skills are above average, but you have no class, eh?
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
腕は そこそこだけど 品がないわね
エリス！
（咆哮(ほうこう)）
Ellis!
Are you okay?!
（上条）大丈夫ですか？
（黄泉川）あっ…
Kid, what are you doing in a place like this?!
（黄泉川）
少年！
こんな所で何してんじゃん？
Umm, I-
（上条）あの… 俺は…
（黄泉川）あっ…
月詠(つくよみ)先生んとこの悪ガキじゃん
You're Tsukuyomi-sensei's brat.
Where do you think you're going, kid?!
どこ行こうとしてんの？　少年！
フフフッ… こんにちは
Hello there.
おや　幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)か
Oh, it's you, Imagine Breaker.
The Key to the Imaginary Number Sector isn't with you, I see.
虚数学区のカギは
一緒ではないのね
What was the name of that kid again?
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
何ていったかしら？
あのガキの名前
まあ ぶち殺すのは
あのガキでなくてもいいし
Well, the one I need to kill doesn't have to be her.
Killing you would be the same!
てめえを殺したって
問題ねえってわけだ！
The earth is my power.
大地は私の力
No one will be able to stand on this earth after confronting Ellis.
エリスを前にしたら 誰も
大地に立つことなどできはしない
お前…！
You...
Not "you".
“お前”ではない
シェリー＝クロムウェルよ
The name's Shelley Cromwell.
But, since you'll be dying here,
まあ ここで死ぬんだし
イギリス清教を名乗ってもね
...it doesn't matter if I say I'm from the English Purist Church.
English Purist Church?!
イギリス清教？
Why is someone from the same organization as Index...
インデックスと
同じ組織の人間が なんで…
I want war.
戦争を起こすんだよ
その火種が欲しいの
And I want to create the reason.
That's why the more people that know I'm from the English Purist Church, the better!!!
だから 多くの人間に 私が―
イギリス清教の手駒だって
知ってもらわないとね
くそ… 少しでも
あいつに触れることができれば…
Damn it.
If only I could come in contact with that thing just a little bit...
（風斬）あ… あの…
（上条）ハッ…
Umm...
Kazakiri?!
（上条）
風斬！　バカ野郎！
なんで白井を待ってなかった？
You idiot! Why didn't you wait for Shirai?!
あっ あの… だって…
B-Because...
いいから 早く伏せろ！
Who cares, get down right away!
Kazakiri.
（上条）
風斬！
な… 何だ？　これ…
What the hell is this...
H-Huh...
あれ？　メガネ… えっ？
My glasses-
What... is this...
なに これ？
えっ？　そんな…
No...
えっ… こ… こんなのって…
W-What is this...
風斬…
Kazakiri...
（風斬）
イヤ… イヤーッ！
No... No!!!
Kazakiri, no! That way's-
風斬！　おい そっちは…
フフッ… エリス
Ellis.
Kazakiri!!!
風斬！
Let's go, Ellis.
いくぞ エリス　ぶざまで滑稽な
キツネを狩り出しましょう
Let us go hunt down the sorry and ugly little fox.
Gosh, where did they go?
もう…
どこに行ってしまったのかしら
This is troubling...
困りましたわね
（女性）
もう！　開けてよ！
Open up!
I'm worried about those two,
あの２人も心配ですけど
この人たちを
置き去りにはできませんわね
but I can't leave these people here either.
風斬…
Kazakiri...
Damn it.
くそ… 何が どうなってるんだ？
What the hell is going on?
Hello?
（小萌(こもえ)）
あっ 上条ちゃんですか？
Kamijyo-chan, is that you?
We finally got in touch with you.
（小萌）
ようやく つながったです
姫神ちゃんが連絡を取りたくて
何度も電話してたんですけど
Himegami-chan was trying to contact you and tried calling many times, but...
Himegami tried to call me?
姫神が俺に？
（小萌）
先生からも 大事な話があるのです
Sensei has something important to tell you, as well.
Sorry, but I don't have time right now.
悪いけど
今 それどころじゃないんです
So-
だから…
（小萌）
風斬氷華さんのことじゃ
ないですか？
Isn't this about Kazakiri Hyouka-san?
Listen carefully.
よく聞いてください
I'm not sure how this happened,
どういうわけか分かりませんが
学校の周囲の防犯カメラには―
but Kazakiri Hyouka-san could not be seen on any of the school's surveillance cameras.
風斬氷華さんの姿は
全く映っていなかったのです
（小萌）
あのとき
上条ちゃんのそばにいた彼女は―
We don't know how she got on the campus all the way to sitting next to you, Kamijyo-chan, back there.
一体 どこから
学校に入ってきたのでしょう？
H-Hold it!
ちょ… ちょっと待ってください
どういうことなんですか？
What does that mean?!
風斬氷華さんには―
AIM Dispersion Field... Kazakiri Hyouka-san definitely has something to do with this.
ＡＩＭ拡散力場が
深く関わっていると思われるのです
What does that have to do with Kazakiri?
（上条）
それが 風斬と どう関係が？
This is just a theory.
あくまで推測なのですけど
The generation of bioelectricity,
生体電気の発生と
それに伴う磁場の形成
the formation of a magnetic field,
the consumption of oxygen and release of carbon dioxide, etc.
酸素の消費と
二酸化炭素の放出などなど
If all this "data" that is human-like was combined together, wouldn't that create a "human"?
人間を形作っているデータが
全て そろっていたとしたら―
そこに“人間”がいるということに
なりませんか？
There is a large variety of espers in Academy City,
（小萌）
学園都市には
さまざまな能力者がいて
and they are unconsciously releasing small amounts of power.
常に 無意識のうちに
微弱の力を放出しています
When all those are combined,
wouldn't they create some meaning?
（小萌）
それが いくつも重なり合って
ひとつの意味を成すとしたら？
What if all those created Kazakiri Hyouka?
それらが 風斬氷華さんを
作ってしまっているとしたら？
えっ… いくら何でも それは…
That's just too hard to believe...
（小萌）
風斬氷華さんの目撃談は
昔からあったそうなのです
The witness accounts of Kazakiri Hyouka
have been occurring for a long time now.
Back then, she was probably a ghost-like, vague existence.
恐らく 当時の彼女は―
幽霊みたいな
曖昧な存在だったと思うのです
But, it seemed Kazakiri didn't realize that herself.
けど 風斬自身は そのことに
気づいてなかったみたいなんですよ
If you assume that she thought she has always been a human,
（小萌）
ずっと自分が人間だと
思い込んでいたのだとすれば―
本人は 何の疑問も
持たなかったはずなのですよ
then she herself would never have had that suspicion to begin with.
The bottom line is, Kazakiri Hyouka-san is not a human.
結論を言ってしまえば
風斬氷華さんは人間ではありません
（小萌）
ＡＩＭ拡散力場が生んだ―
She is really a physical phenomenon that the AIM Dispersion Fields have given birth to.
物理現象のひとつということに
なりますね
なんだ？　それ…
そんな ひどいことって…
What does... that mean...
How could something so cruel-
Cruel, you say?
（小萌）
“ひどい”ですか？
Listen to me, Kamijyo-chan.
いいですか 上条ちゃん
Even if we combine all the elements that constitute a human,
人間に必要な要素を
兼ね備えていたとしても―
Kazakiri Hyouka-san is still not a human.
やはり
風斬氷華さんは人間ではありません
However, what's the reason that she can't be considered a human?
（小萌）
ですが そもそも 人でないと
いけない理由は何ですか？
What did you think of her, from your eyes, Kamijyo-chan?
上条ちゃんの目から見て
彼女は どうでしたか？
Was Kazakiri Hyouka-san just an illusion that just stood here, lifeless, heartless, doing nothing?
（小萌）
風斬氷華さんは ただ
そこに たたずんでいるだけの―
命も心もない幻想に
すぎませんでしたか？
Was she so light of an existence that we can abandon her?
簡単に失われていいほど
軽い存在でしたか？
No!
違う　そんなわけがあるか！
Of course not!
Even if she was just an illusion that would vanish when touched,
触れれば消えてしまうような
幻想にすぎなくたって…
that doesn't mean she could just disappear like that.
あいつが消えていい理由になんか
なってたまるか
There you go!
それでいいのです！
先生は まっすぐな方向に
育ってくれる子羊ちゃんは―
Sensei loves little sheep that are brought up the right way!
大好きなのですよ
Don't make your precious friend cry, okay?
くれぐれも 大事なお友達を
泣かさないようにしてくださいね
Well then!
（小萌）
それではなのです
ウウ… ハァ…
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
フフフッ… 何なのかしらね
What are you?
They call you the Key to the Imaginary Number Sector, but just looking at you,
虚数学区のカギとかいわれて
どんなものかと思ってみれば―
this is your true identity?
正体は こんなもんかよ
こんなものを大事に抱え込むなんざ
科学ってのは狂ってるよな？
Science sure is messed up to be dearly cherishing something like you.
Why?!
どうして？
なんで こんなひどいこと…
Why are you doing such cruel-
えっ？　なに？
ひょっとして あなた―
Huh? What?
Are you one of those that say
"I'm scared of dying" or the likes?
自分が死ぬのが怖いとか
言っちゃう人かしら？
Come on now.
おいおい
いいかげんに気づきなさいっての
Take note already.
てめえが
まともな人間なはずねえだろうが
There's no way you're a normal human.
Don't be looking so shocked.
なに真っ青な顔してんだよ？　ほら
See?
私が あなたにしていることって
この程度のことでしょう？
What I'm doing to you is the same as this.
You understand now?
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
これで分かったでしょう？
あなたはエリスと同じ化け物
You're just like Ellis, a monster.
You have no resting place.
てめえの居場所なんか
どこにもないってことが
I'm not sure, but Hyouka's my friend!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
よく分かんなくても
氷華は友達だもん
Yes, join us, Hyouka!
そうだ　氷華も一緒に行こう
Here, Hyouka.
はい 氷華　半分こ
Half and half.
（ｼｪﾘｰ）泣くなよ 化け物
（風斬）ハッ…
Don't cry now, monster.
It's rather disgusting for you to be crying anyway!
あなたが泣いても
気持ちが悪いだけなんだし
待たせちまったみたいだな
Kept you waiting there, eh?
It's okay now.
もう大丈夫だ
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
いいか？　風斬
Listen up, Kazakiri.
The kindness you came in touch with isn't an illusion!
お前が触れた優しさは
幻想なんかじゃない
Even if you're not human, we will save you no matter what!
お前が人間じゃないとしても
俺たちは 必ず お前を助ける
次回 「風斬氷華(トモダチ)」
Next time, "Friend".
When science and magic cross paths,
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
this epic will begin!